Rienow, Leona; Papers mss025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Leona Train Rienow Papers1856-1988
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Rienow, Leona Train
mss025
2.78 cubic ft.
This collection documents Leona Train Rienow's professional career as a writer. The papers contain a significant number of drafts of Leona Train Rienow's manuscripts, papers concerning her research for her books and articles, and correspondence files.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in June 1988.
Biographical Sketch
Leona Train Rienow was born in Duluth, Minnesota in 1903, but moved when she was one year old to the mining site of Chisholm, Minnesota. She received a B.A. from the University of Chicago and her Master's from the University of Minnesota. In 1931, she married Robert Rienow while he was attending West Point. She toured Europe in 1948 and Italy in 1953. She also traveled on a tramp freighter around the Mediterranean visiting Cairo, Alexandria, Beirut, and Damascus. Her interests included birds and bird-watching, baking, camping, canoeing, touring, forestry, the environment, politics, photography, roses, cats, prehistory, and the Middle Ages.
Leona Train Rienow authored books, most of which were for children, short stories, and articles. Her books included The Bewitched Caverns (1948), The Dark Pool (1949), The Year of the Last Eagle (1970), and Unbottled Scotch (1987). She also co-authored a number of books with her husband including Our New Life with the Atom (1959), Of Snuff, Sin and the Senate (1965), The Lonely Quest: the Evolution of Presidential Leadership (1966), Moment in the Sun: a Report on the Deteriorating Quality of the American Environment (1967), Man Against His Environment (1970), and The Great Unwanteds Want Us: Illegal Aliens-too late to close the gates? (1980).
Leona Train Rienow died of a stroke in 1983 at Child's Hospital in Albany, New York. She was eighty years old.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents Leona Train Rienow's professional career as a writer. The papers contain a significant number of drafts of Leona Train Rienow's manuscripts, papers concerning her research for her books and articles, and correspondence files. Much of the correspondence concerns publishers and editors of various magazines and publishing houses.
Strengths of this collection include the many drafts of manuscripts that document the changes that Leona Train Rienow made to her works over a span of many years. Weaknesses of this collection include a lack of material on Rienow's personal life outside of her professional career as a writer and her environmental activism. There are also many whole newspaper sections, news clippings, and notes written on scraps of paper whose significance is often unclear. Also, this collection does not comprise drafts of all her books and articles.
Preservation concerns include yellowing and/or brittle paper which is often folded and/or wavy, foxing on the edges of some manuscripts, corners or pieces torn out of some pages, and fire damage.
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information on the environmental and political issues that were of concern to Rienow throughout her life. Of particular note are the collections of her husband Robert Rienow (UA-902.009), Environmental Advocates of New York (APAP-104), Nancy Papish (APAP-144), Environmental Clearinghouse, Inc. (APAP-180), and Vincent J. Schaefer (UA-902.010). For a complete list of related collections see the subject guides for Conservation and the Environment and Literature.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Literature; Conservation and the Environment; Women authors; American fiction--Women authors; Rienow, Leona Train--Manuscripts; Minnesota--Chisholm; Manuscripts (document genre); Research (document genres); Correspondence; Clippings (information artifacts); Rienow, Leona Train
- Typescripts, ca. 1952-1955; Undated; 1; 2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of drafts of several books, short stories, and articles authored by Leona Train Rienow, many of which are undated. Drafts pertaining to her books include The Friar's Lantern; A Kingdom for Ethelfleda; Locusts; Mystery of the Midnight Fire; Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter; Mesaba Plunder; and River without Any End. Drafts of short stories include Bed and Breakfast; Cradle of Humanity; Fair on Morrow; Gekocht Aardappelen; Gory Glory; The Great Salt Age; Hospitality-Old World Style; I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Guest Room; I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Spare Room; It's the British Air!; Monuments by God; Peasoup and Snails; Peeking Gendarmes; Professor, Your Goodwill is Showing; Screwball Authorities: Our Idolatry of Big Names; Tourists Delight; You Can't Buck Tradition; and We Become Class-Conscious.
  - Bed and Breakfast, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 1)
  - Cradle of Humanity, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 2)
  - Fair on Morrow, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 3)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Preliminaries, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 4)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter I, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 5)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter II, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 6)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter III, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 7)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter IV, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 8)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter V, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 9)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VI, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 10)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VII, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 11)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VIII, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 12)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter IX, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 13)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter X, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 14)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XI, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 15)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XII, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 16)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XIII, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 17)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XIV, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 18)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XV, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 19)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XVI, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 20)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XVII, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 21)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XX, 1959 June (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 22)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter I, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 23)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter II, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 24)
  - The Friar's Lantern Chapter IV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 25)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 26)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter I, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 27)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter II, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 28)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter III, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 29)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter IV, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 30)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter V, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 31)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter VI, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 32)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter VII, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 33)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter IX, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 34)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter X, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 35)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XI, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 36)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XII, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 37)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIII, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 38)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIV, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 39)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XV, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 40)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XVI, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 41)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XVII, 1952 May (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 42)
  - Gekocht Aardappelen, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 43)
  - Gory Glory, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 44)
  - The Great Salt Age, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 45)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Title Page and Diagram, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 46)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter I, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 47)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter II, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 48)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter III, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 49)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 50)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter V, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 51)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 52)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 53)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 54)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 55)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter X, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 56)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 57)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 58)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 59)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 60)
  - Hospitality-Old Word Style, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 61)
  - I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Guest Room, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 62)
  - I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Spare Room, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 63)
  - It's the British Air!, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 64)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Editor's Note, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 65)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Outline of Continuing Action, 1952 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 66)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Title Page and Chapter I, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 67)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter I, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 68)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter II, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 69)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter II, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 70)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter III, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 71)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter III, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 72)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 73)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IV, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 74)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter V, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 75)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 76)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VI, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 77)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 78)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 79)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VIII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 80)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 81)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IX, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 82)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter X, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 83)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter X, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 84)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 85)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XI, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 86)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 87)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 88)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 89)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 90)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 91)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIV, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 92)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 93)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XV, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 94)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 95)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVI, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 96)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 97)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVIII, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 98)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVIII, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 99)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIX, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 100)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIX, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 101)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XX, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 102)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XX, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 103)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XXI, Undated (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 104)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XXI, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 105)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Discard Sheets, 1952 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 106)
  - Locusts, Chapter I, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 107)
  - Locusts, A, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 108)
  - Locusts, B, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 109)
  - Locusts, Chapter II, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 110)
  - Locusts, Chapter III, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 111)
  - Locusts, Chapter III, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 112)
  - Locusts, Chapter IV, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 113)
  - Locusts, Chapter IV, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 114)
  - Locusts, Chapter V, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 115)
  - Locusts, Chapter VI, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 116)
  - Locusts, Chapter VI, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 117)
  - Locusts, Chapter VII, 1953 November (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 118)
  - Locusts, Chapter VII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 119)
  - Locusts, Chapter VIII, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 120)
  - Locusts, Chapter VIII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 121)
  - Locusts, Chapter IX, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 122)
  - Locusts, Chapter X, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 123)
  - Locusts, Chapter X, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 124)
  - Locusts, Chapter XI, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 125)
  - Locusts, Chapter XI, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 126)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 127)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIV, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 128)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIV, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 129)
  - Locusts, Chapter XV, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 130)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVI, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 131)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 132)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVIII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 133)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIX, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 134)
  - Locusts, Chapter XX, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 135)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXI, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 136)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXI, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 137)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXII, 1951 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 138)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 139)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIII, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Typescripts), Folder 140)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 1)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV a, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 2)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 3)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXV, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 4)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 5)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVI, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 6)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 7)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 8)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 9)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVIII, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 10)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 11)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 12)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 13)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX a, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 14)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX a, 1953 April (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 15)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXX, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 16)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXI, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 17)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 18)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXII, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 19)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 20)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIII, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 21)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 22)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 23)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 24)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 25)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 26)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 27)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIX, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 28)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIX, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 29)
  - Locusts, Chapter XL, 1951 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 30)
  - Locusts, Chapter XL, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 31)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 32)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 33)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 34)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 35)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 36)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 37)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 38)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 39)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 40)
  - Locusts, Chapter L, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 41)
  - Locusts, Chapter LI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 42)
  - Locusts, Chapter LII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 43)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 44)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 45)
  - Locusts, Chapter LV, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 46)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 47)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 48)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 49)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIX, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 50)
  - Locusts, Chapter LX, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 51)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXI, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 52)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 53)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXIII, 1955 (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 54)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Author's Note, Title Page, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 55)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter I, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 56)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter II, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 57)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter III, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 58)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 59)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter V, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 60)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 61)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 62)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 63)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 64)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter X, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 65)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter X, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 66)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 67)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 68)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 69)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 70)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 71)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 72)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 73)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 74)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 75)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 76)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 77)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 78)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 79)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 80)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 81)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 82)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 83)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 84)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 85)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 86)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 87)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 88)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 89)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 90)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 91)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 92)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVI a, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 93)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 94)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 95)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIX, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 96)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XL, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 97)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLI, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 98)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 99)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLIII, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 100)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLIV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 101)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XLV, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 102)
  - Monuments By God, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 103)
  - The Mystery of the Midnight Fires, Chapter I, Undated (Box 2 (1-Typescripts), Folder 104)